

Michael Ziegler

Mikeziegler123.github.io



4839 43rd Avenue Kenosha, WI 53144



Mobile(US): +1(815) 321-2752



Mikeziegler123@gmail.com

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Hi, I'm Mike: I am a Software developer, innovation & technology professional, motivated learner, and enthusiastic team member. I am excited each day to solve problems, learn more, and continue to strengthen my technical skills. I have held responsible roles in a variety of professional fields, and my unique variety of industry has led me toward creative solutions to complex problems working in the field of technology.

- ★ Graduated from Middle Tennessee State University on May 4th, 2019.
- **★** Studied Computer Science & Law.
- **★** Natural problem solver with strong attention to programming detail.
- ★ 5+ years technical development skills.

Knowledgeable & Pursuant in Learning: AWS developer (associate) Certification, SaaS, best programming practices, SQL & big data analysis, web application development, AI, scalability, and linear regression.

PROFESSIONAL

Infosys, — Associate Developer Milwaulkee, WI | Downtown Milwaukee

miiwaaikee, wi | Downtown miiwaakee

February 2021 - **Present** Phone: (414) 353-4888

- Software development - Develop code and document artifacts including test plans to output meets SLA requirements. Production Support - conduct analysis,

Snap-On Incorporated,— IT Support Analyst *Kenosha, WI | Snap-On corporate office*

January 2021 - February 2021 Phone: (877) 762-7664

- Investigated, analyzed, and fully resolved an average of 90 cases per week utilizing telephone queues and ticketing system.
- Examined and assessed challenging hardware issues.
- Applied specialized Dell diagnostics tools to determine and repair various hardware issues.
- Re-imaged Windows 10 systems to correct issues or be redeployed to other users.
- Configured and supported both proprietary and 3rd party software.

The City Of Lake Forest, — IT Internship

Lake Forest, IL | Innovation & Technology Division

January 2020 - January 2021 Phone: (847) 810-3591

- Perform Client/Server application & infrastructure support on industry wide technology.
- Deployment/testing of tools and frameworks in an Agile team environment.
- Provide help-desk support via remote connection, phone, email, Powershell, Putty, and on-premise maintenance services, for 14 buildings using over 70 software systems citywide.



: Github.com/Mikeziegler123

in

Linkedin.com/in/Michael-Ziegler-6b19891

EDUCATIONAL

Middle Tennessee State University,

B.S. 2019 Murfreesboro, TN

Computer Science | GPA: 3.0

Pre-Law Cognate | GPA: 3.0

MIDDLE TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY



Dell DCSE 1000 Client Foundations 2021

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: Proficiency 4+ years

★ C++ [Visual Studio 2019, CodeLite]★ Python [Idle, Tkinter, BeautifulSoup]

★ Java [Visual Studio 2019, Eclipse, Selenium, JFX]

★ SQL [M-SQLExpress, Postgres, MYSQL]★ OBJ-C [Visual Studio 2019, LeetCode]

INTERNSHIP

Pre-Law Internship: Judge McFarlin | Tidwell Murfreesboro, TN | City Courthouse | Judges Office

- Positioned for legal experience, remembered for technological help and knowledge.
- Offered to run the social media campaign for Judge Tidwell's next election cycle.

Pre-Law Internship: Senator Pamela J Althoff Crystal Lake, IL | Senator's Office

- Constituent data entry during an active election cycle; election event planning.

Curriculum & Academic Policy Council Member Crystal Lake, IL | McHenry County College

- Student Representative
- Nominated Board position.

McHenry County College Student Senator Crystal Lake, IL | McHenry County College

- Active within student government: 2009-2013

CV: Updated: 02//2021

Employment History:

Infosys - Associate Developer 2021-Current

• Software Development / Programming - Knowledge of how to develop code and document artifacts including unit test plans and ensure that the output is as per the given specifications and SLAs.

- Testing Perform testing activities (Functional, Integration, System, User experience) based on the plans and in line with defined processes with guidance from supervisor.
- Production Support Respond to the issues assigned, conduct analysis, suggest / implement workarounds, communicate to all the stakeholders and close issues as per the agreed timelines.
- Knowledge Management activities including documentation and knowledge gathering of the modules he / she is working on.

Snap-On Corporate Office - Associate IT Support Analyst 2021-2021

- Investigated, analyzed, and fully resolved an average of 90 cases per week utilizing telephone queues and ticketing system.
- Examined and assessed challenging hardware issues for Dell desktops and laptops, HP printers and scanners, multi-function printers, docking stations, computer peripherals, iPhone, iPad, Android, and Windows based phones.
- Applied a specialized Dell diagnostics tool to determine and repair various hardware issues.
- Re-imaged Windows 10 systems to correct issues or be redeployed to other users.
- Configured and supported proprietary and 3rd party software.

The City Of Lake Forest, Department of Innovation & Technology - Intern 2020-Current

- Perform Client/Server application & infrastructure support on industry wide technology.
- Deployment/testing of tools and frameworks in an Agile team environment.
- \bullet Effectively communicate verbally and in writing to immediate team members
- Perform technical maintenance on hardware and software for all city municipalities ranging from police vehicle radio communications, to data center server/switch repair/replacement/installation.
- Design & debug SQL queries to develop custom report solutions to simplify our analysis in situations including: new hardware roll-outs & cascading old hardware, software license inventory, etc.
- Administer user moves, adds, and changes in the city's active directory environment and associated systems.
- Administered help-desk Support via remote connection, phone, email, silently using Powershell & Network administrator Services, and on-premise maintenance services, for 13 city buildings using over 70 software systems.
- I work with a truly great team of only 4(including myself) individuals running around solving all of the city's technology problems, as well as meeting every week to discuss what we can do to push the city further forward with technology.

Rogers Enterprise, Inc. Assistant Manager 2019 - 2020

• Designed and implemented VBScript/Python automation scripts to resolve redundancies of daily operations & vamp up internal network security.

- Recruited, interviewed and trained new staff during management transition and major software changes.
- I was personally recruited by an old coworker (now manager) from a previous jewelry store.
- Assumed the role of assistant manager, during management transition.
- Worked with a new manager to hire new staff, interview, & optimize day-to-day store operations.
- Personally sold over \$38,000 in the month of December, exceeding my Platinum(highest tier) goal.

Specialized Pools Owner 2016-2019

- Started this business while finishing my degree in Tennessee. Specialized Pools flourished enough to supersede my banking position, and still runs today under management of my younger brother, who is now also finishing his degree in computer science at the same school.
- Above ground swimming pool services: Pool Openings, Pool Closings, Water Chemistry, Liner Replacements, Repairs & Maintenance, and Pool Builds.
- Performed all web marketing & website design for the business.
- Set up meetings with local pool supply distributors, to gain their customers in case they require great services.
- Master of my trade / Extensive knowledge of tools and methods.
- Received training from engineers and skilled individuals.
- Supervised hired, and trained employees.

US Bank Peak-Time Teller 2016-2017

- Consulted with customers and provided account services including:
- Receiving deposits
- Loan payments
- Cashing checks
- Issuing savings bonds
- Withdrawals
- Exceptional bookkeeping
- Issuing cashier's checks
- Traveler's checks
- series E bonds
- Independently preserved the location's customer service scores during a downturn.
- Answered any questions regarding our compliance with established federal regulations and protocols, and happily discussed any additional banking services we offered.

Erica's Fine Jewelry (Kenosha, WI) 2015-2016

- Accountable for store Sales day to day, building very Strong Customer Relationships
- Responsible for handling Routine Financial Transactions.
- Responsible for accepting and verifying large customer Payments, Deposits, and Credit Payments.
- Shipping and receiving both customer and vendor shipments, distributing, organizing, and stocking through stores.
- Educating each customer on the vast amount of options they have in the jewelry industry, from extensive diamond and gemstone education using tools from our diamond laboratory to drawing, customizing, and creating a custom piece.

Kay Jewelers Assistant Manager - Woodfield Mall 2012-2015

- Assured that my team and I achieve our standards to reach our goals.
- Calculate, post, review, and discuss sales goals daily for the store, every employee, including myself.
- Responsible for opening and closing the store(s), and on call for responding and securing the store in the event the security alarm is tripped.
- Exceeded goals include: Sales, repair dollars, credit applications, extended service plans, and add on items.
- Personally sold over 220,000 in 2012-2013. My team and I had sold over 1.4 million.
- Conducted store meetings and disciplinary actions when needed.

Transfer/receive shipments, check in merchandise.

• Balance all registers each night.

Commission based sales environment.

- Management Training System certification completed
- Certified as a Diamontologist through Diamond Council of America.

.....

Mchenry County College Student Orientation Leader - Crystal Lake, IL 2011-2012

- Run Summer Orientations for new student and parents at MCC
- New program, Developing Ideas to make it successful.
- Office Work: Sending mailers, phone assistance, organizing all paperwork into files.

Education:

Middle Tennessee State University (Current)

• B.S. Pre-Law/Computer Science 2019.

College of Lake County

• Acquired further credits toward my Bachelors program

Mchenry County College

Acquired credits towards my Associate degree in science 2013

Johnsburg High School

• Graduated from Johnsburg High School in 2009.

Internships:

Competitive/Paid IT Internship: IT Director-Jim Shaw, Assistant IT Director-Joe Gabanski Lake Forest, IL | The City of Lake Forest | Department of Innovation & Technology

Pre-Law Internship: Judge McFarlin | Tidwell
Murfreesboro, TN | City Courthouse | Judges Office

Pre-Law Internship: Senator Pamela J Althoff Crystal Lake, IL | Senator's Office

Curriculum & Academic Policy Council Member

Crystal Lake, IL | McHenry County College

McHenry County College Student Senator

Crystal Lake, IL | McHenry County College

Contributions & Affiliations:

- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner 2020
- HackMT Hackathon, Middle Tennessee State University, 2018
- Certified Diamontologist via The Diamond Council of America 2014
- Kay Jeweler's management training program certification 2013
- Appointed as student representative on Board of Conduct, McHenry County College 2012
- Student Orientation Leader. Mchenry County College 2011-2012
- McHenry County College Curriculum and Academic Policy Representative Nominated 2011
- Door to door sales associate for subcontractor of Comcast selling Xfinity package 2011
- Student representative for lobby day, McHenry County College Springfield, IL 2011
- McHenry County College L.E.A.D(leadership, excellence, & development) member 2009-2011
- Appointed Student Senator on Executive board, McHenry County College 2010
- Wilmot Mountain Group Ski/Snowboard Instructor 2008-2010.
- Played Bass/Guitar in 3 performing bands, one of which toured to Nashville, TN.